KANAV SHARMA

Data Scientist

CONTACT

9469850599

kanav608@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanav-

sharma-896b1021b/

EDUCATION

SURESH GYAN VIHAR UNIVERSITY, JAIPUR

BTech CSE 7.9 CGPA

2015-2019

SKILLS

Programming Languages: R, Python

Software:

Gitlab, Docker, SQL, R Studio,

Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau, AWS

Tools:

Sklearn, Pandas, NumPy, Selenium,

Scipy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, R-libraries

SUMMARY

An experienced Data Scientist with close to 4 years experience .I have hands on experience in analyzing & interpreting data with good numerical accuracy. I believe I have the ability to juggle an array of tasks whilst staying focused on priorities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR ASSOCIATE

Kreate Technologies Pvt Ltd

Feb 2020 - Present

- Contributed to **3x revenue growth** by using different statistical techniques, dealing with **time series data**.
- Reduction of MAPE by 40% by creating ensemble model out of best models from existing models like tree based, boosting models
- Reduction of MAPE by 35% for existing clients by extracting pixel values from images using selenium(Python)
- Reduction of MAPE by 22% by using Multiple linear regression.
- Prepared accuracy report on a regular interval of time using Tableau.
- Use AWS services like EC2, S3, SageMaker for increasing productivity. .
- Used Python, R & SQL for Data Cleaning, Feature Engineering, Feature Selection, Data Analysis & ETL.

DATA SCIENTIST

RoboMQ Pvt Ltd

Jan 2019- Jan 2020

- Predict favorable condition for a Tennis match using Decision Tree
 (Classification) with ID3 algorithm. Accuracy Score: 0.84
- Assessed the chances of a user going to access the Contact Us link through certain links in the website using Logistic Regression

(Classification). Accuracy Score: 0.86

ACADEMIC PROJECT

Crime Management System

• An integrated system using **PHP & SQL** where all crimes and investigations can be created, read, updated and deleted using valid credentials.

Restaurant Management System

A GUI was built using Python and has upgraded GST rates. The GUI helps
users to create, update details on the billing system of restaurants. Tkinter
is used in this project